Have you ever wondered how computers are able
to generate art,
write stories, and even create music?
Well, it's because of a new type of AI technology called
Generative AI.
Generative AI is a type of artificial intelligence that's
able to learn from patterns and data and generate new data based
on what it has learned.
Today, the most widely used types of Generative AI are models that
are generating text or images such as ChatGPT or Midjourney.
But these models can be applied across a lot of different
types of data,
including audio, video, 3D models,
and the list is growing every day.
And that ability to generate new data has really democratized
access to AI.
In the past, to use AI, you would have to train one
of these models yourself, which would require you to have
big data and an experienced team that can go and build that model.
But now, because these models have learned that core task,
such as generating text, they are actually able to be
applied across a whole variety of new tasks, such as summarizing
documents,
copywriting, writing code and a lot more.
There are a growing number of companies,
including OpenAI, who are building these models and
then making them available to the public.
So, if you've ever wanted to use AI in your business or in your work,
there's never been a better time, thanks to Generative AI.