I'm going to explain the basics of how ChatGPT works so that you can
be more informed and get the most out of this new technology.
ChatGPT is an application built on top of an AI model called GPT.
GPT is a massive AI model that was trained on billions of words
across a bunch of books, a lot of the internet and
a lot of Wikipedia.
GPT works by taking input, text and using what its learned
about language to predict the next most likely word.
Once it has that word, it does the same process again to
predict the next most likely word.
At its core, all GPT is doing is predicting the next
most likely word,
given the preceding words.
And one of the most exciting things about GPT is because it's
learned to predict words so effectively,
it's able to perform a lot of other tasks.
It can be customized and even fine tuned to get better at specific
tasks or use cases.
And ChatGPT is a great example of this.
OpenAI fine tuned GPT to be better at chat by feeding it a bunch of
examples of chat conversations.