Writing a good prompt helps us get the most out of AI tools
like ChatGPT.
Prompting is a way to give these AI models direction so it can
understand our task and then help us complete it.
But to get the best results, you need to know how to
craft a good prompt.
And most people who struggle with prompting are making
the same mistake.
They're being too generic and expecting that AI is just
going to read our minds.
For example, if you ask something generic like write a social media
caption for a bakery, you're going to get something
generic in return.
So what makes a good prompt?
Well, first, you need to create context. Before you ask the
AI model to do something, you need to help it understand
the task.
One best practice is to tell the AI what you want it
to act as,
such as a social media marketer, which helps roleplay and have
more context for your task.
Second, you want to be specific and give the AI a more concrete
task at hand.
Like you will be responsible for writing engaging social media
captions for Instagram feed, for our bakery.
You write in our brand voice, which is friendly,
casual and witty.
Then you want to give clear instructions for what you
expect in return.
For example, saying, my first request is I need a
caption for a blue boy birthday cake.
Finally, be as simple and concise with your language as possible.
And if you find yourself getting wordy,
you can even ask the AI model to rewrite your prompt
to be more concise.
Keep these tips in mind and you're going to be able to get the most
out of AI models like ChatGPT.