One of the most powerful things about ChatGPT is just how good it
is at completing your task just from the prompt that you give it.
But, if you find yourself wanting to teach ChatGPT a more complex
task or having more control over the formatting of the output,
then try giving ChatGPT examples.
This is an approach called fuchsia learning where you give ChatGPT a
few shots or examples and it learns how to do that task.
To do this, add structure to your prompts that show example
inputs and outputs for your task.
When you give examples, you have more control over
how ChatGPT responds.
Let's look at a quick example.
Here, I've asked ChatGPT to generate a dog name.
Now, if I want more control over the formatting of the output,
I can give it an example.
As you see here,
now the format of the output matches what I gave
it in my example.
Keep in mind that you'll need to share these examples each time you
start a new thread, because ChatGPT only remembers the examples within
the context of your prompt.
But this can be a very powerful tool for getting more specific
results from ChatGPT.