Here are three easy steps to start using AI in your business.
The first is to develop AI literacy,
which is an understanding of what is AI and how can it be used.
For example, today AI can be used to create content,
summarize, synthesize, predict, classify and a lot more.
You also need to understand the limitations of AI so that you can
make smart decisions about how to apply it.
The second step is to get a deeper understanding of the
capabilities of AI.
The best way to do this is to start playing with some of the AI
tools that are launching every day,
Focus on learning and having a little bit of fun and then try to
find tools across a variety of applications from text to image, to
audio, to video, to data, and whatever else you could find.
The best way to develop AI literacy is just to start trying stuff.
And once you're ready to start putting AI to work for you,
start by identifying a few internal tasks that
you want to have AI
start to help you with.
While it can be tempting to jump to building a new product or
service for your end customer first,
I recommend that you start with an internal use case because you're
going to learn a lot more from having first-hand experience.
I hope that these steps help you get started with AI in your
work or organization.