AI tools like ChatGPT are incredibly powerful,
but it's important to keep people involved in the process.
In this video, I'll explain why. AI models are impressive,
but they are far from perfect.
If you've ever used ChatGPT,
you've seen that the outputs of these tools can be questionable,
and that's true for other tools like DALL-E,
Midjourney and more.
That's why it's important to keep a human involved in the process to
provide oversight and make sure that the results are
of high quality.
This is especially important in high stakes domains such as code
generation or showing the output to an end customer.
For example, I would not recommend setting up an automated email
response where you have GPT generating the results unless you
are certain that it is very good and does not generate
any weird responses.
I think it's much better to think about the results out of these AI
models as a first draft and then you should review and edit that
output to get it to the quality level that you want.
If you aren't going to review every single response,
at a minimum, you should be reviewing results on
a regular basis.
And one last tip is that you should keep track of what the AI
model generated versus what's your final result after
you've edited it.
This can provide good context of how well is the AI model doing at
the first pass draft of your task.