Have you ever used ChatGPT and found that the output
was very inaccurate?
Let's talk about why that happens.
ChatGPT is a powerful AI model, but at its, core all it's doing is
learning patterns from words and using that to predict the
next most likely word.
This allows it to generate text that sounds coherent
and confident,
but that doesn't always mean that it's accurate.
This is known as the hallucination problem,
when the generated text doesn't match the underlying data
that it was given.
For example, ChatGPT can make up non existent biographies of
fake famous people.
It can give historical context on fake events,
and it can even provide pretty compelling logic that's not
actually conceptually sound.
To reduce this, you can write better prompts or
provide additional context or data for the AI model to use.
However, it's still not foolproof, and that's why you should always
review the output coming out of these models to ensure that
they are accurate.