What happens to your data when you're using AI models
like ChatGPT?
If you're using AI at work or for your business,
this is an important question to ask and understand.
Now, the details of how data is used varies based on the
product or model.
And if you have specific questions,
I recommend talking to a lawyer about data ownership and privacy.
But, here are three questions which are good to ask and keep in mind.
First is, do you have commercial rights to the output?
For example, if you want to use an image that you've generated
using an AI tool, you'll need to understand the
licensing that comes with the tool that you're using.
Second is, are your inputs and outputs being used to improve
the underlying AI model?
This is very common for tech products and it was the reason why
ChatGPT was launched and given for free to the public.
They specifically call this a research preview
for those purposes. You can learn about how this works
for any product that you're using, usually by looking at the
terms of service.
Third is, what data am I sharing in order to use the service?
Many of the AI products today help us with productivity,
and so they usually need access to some of our tools,
such as our email or our Google Drive and other sensitive
information.
You should understand and only give access to the companies and
products that you trust.
And last, I recommend having an open conversation about this with
your work or business, because these are very important questions
to have in mind as you're trying to use AI in your work
or day to day.