How are people using AI in their day to day work?
First, I like to think of AI almost like you're delegating work
to an intern or someone that's new on your team.
I think it's a good analogy because, just like you'd have to
give that person context, you're going to need to give
the AI context as well.
And by thinking about it as delegating,
you can reflect on what are the things that you love to do and how
could you delegate the mundane work that you don't
like doing to AI?
We are seeing AI be applied across almost every domain,
but some of the most mature ones are AI in marketing,
customer support, sales and even software
development.
Within marketing, you can use AI to help you create
marketing materials such as emails and social media posts and sales.
AI can help you generate personalized outreach,
research your customer and even summarize meeting notes from a
sales call. In internal operations,
people are using AI to create the first draft of project plans,
drafting proposals and even drafting slide decks for
presentations. In software engineering AI is even helping
people write code in a fraction of the time.
There's no shortage of ways to use AI across every domain.
The best place to start is just to try a bunch of tools and see how
AI could help you in your work.